Congrats! You've reached
the end of this section.
We've covered some really important
aspects of implementation, tracking, and
quality, in this course.
We discussed why the tracking process is
essential to building confidence in your
team and how important knowing
the progress of a project is.
To communicate this, you learned how to
use various types of tracking methods, like
Gantt charts, roadmaps, and
burndown charts.
You also learned that roadmaps are suitable for tracking high-level milestones,
Gantt charts are useful for
projects with many dependencies,
and burndown charts are better for
more granular,
task-oriented projects that
are on a tight schedule.
You learned which items to track
using these charts, including costs,
the status of key tasks, progress toward
milestones, incoming action items, and
important decisions.
We explored risks and
dependencies, including techniques like
brainstorming to create risk registers,
and we took you through the ROAM
technique, which stands for
resolved, owned, accepted, and mitigated.
You also learned about changes and
dependencies and
how they impact a project.
We also discussed managing and
communicating those risks, changes, and
dependencies.
Whew, that is a lot!
Well done!
Coming up, we'll take you through managing
quality and continuous improvement.
Meet you there.